Jonathan Engelbert

(323) 774-2271 www.jonathanengelbert.com jonathanengelbert@gmail.com

Professional Summary

GIS Analyst and Developer • Full Stack Web developer

ArcGIS Server • ArcGIS SDE • ArcGIS Online • QGIS • Python Scripting • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • SQL • PostGIS • Spatial Analysis • Git • Linux • Server Management

Graduated with honors in GIS and Geography • Magna Cum Laude Graduate • 2017 Excellence in Geography National Award • Designed a class for GIS students at the University of Washington • Invited to participate in the 2017 Radiant GIS Summit as rapporteur • Fluent in Portuguese and Spanish • Work Experience in North America, South America and Europe • Management Experience

Professional Experience

San Francisco Urban Planning Dept (San Francisco, CA)

(August 2017 – Present)

GIS Analyst and Full Stack Developer

Built, tested and maintained software that reduced operational costs an estimated \$100,000 a year, including user validation scripts and data parsing and management programs, both internal and public-facing

Designed and maintained geodatabases in ArcSDE across multiple servers

Built and maintained several web maps and GIS-centric web applications

Created, tested and maintained over 60 Python ETLs, which update, process and load large amounts of data, often daily, across multiple servers and applications

Created over 50 feature classes

Responded to daily ad hoc data requests, including the production of maps and spatial analysis Geo-referenced hundreds of historical maps

Seattle Public Utilities (Seattle, WA)

(May 2016 - June 2017)

Maintenance of drainage and wastewater feature classes representing Seattle Public Utilities and privately-owned infrastructure

Data analysis, production of cartographic products and/or creation of digital datasets.

Built and maintained a web application for tracking of traffic disruption by city-led construction and projects Production tracking (Oracle, MS Access)

Conducted research utilizing a variety of sources (engineering plans, contractor-supplied sketches, field notes, manuals, and documents in support or decision-making

University of Washington (Seattle, WA)

(May 2016 - June 2017)

*Tech support help desk assistant*²

Assisted students and teachers with hardware and software solutions, on and off-site Facilities management assistance

Planning and scheduling of classes and room utilization

Education

Bachelor's in Geography/GIS from University of Washington (Seattle, WA) GPA: 3.96 (Graduated with honors in Geography, 2017)